I have friends in Meridian and I like to do favours for them when I can.
Uthid might be of use to them.
He's a good man so naturally, the Shadow Carja wanna murder him.
So naturally, the Shadow Kharja when a murder him.
I've done some digging and I think he's headed for the Greenclimb.
It won't take those mercenaries long to find him.
He could use some help if you're so inclined.
What makes you think he's on the Greenclimb?
He knows he'll be pursued.
So he needs a hideout that's both familiar and defensible.
He once single-handedly held off an entire bandit clan in those foothills.
My guess is that he'll fall back on what worked before.
How do you know Uthid is innocent?
Look, he feeds orphans from his own rations and personally punishes anyone who hurts the old or infirm.
The idea that he would try to kill Itamen is ridiculous.
He must have found something that can embarrass the priesthood.
Otherwise, Bahavas wouldn't risk marking such a well-regarded man for death.
Alright, made it.
Where did you go Uthid?
Food scraps. I'll bet Uthid stopped to see if he was being followed.
He must have kept going, I've got to catch up.
A dead machine. Uthid's been hunting.
Everything useful has been stripped.
Uthid's been gathering components, probably for ammo.
Uh-oh, Glinthawks looking to scavenge.
Alright, back to Uthid. Where'd he go from here?
Uthid took down a Ravager. Not an easy kill, but worth it for the parts.
Dead Watchers. More scrap for Uthid's stockpile.
The next one doesn't miss.
Uthid!
You're young for a bounty hunter, or am I old for a soldier?
I'm not here for the price on your head Uthid, I believe you're innocent.
Innocent, ha! Come on, then.
UTHID: If this is a trick, it's a good one, you've earned your kill.
ALOY: No tricks, just talk.
Alright, speak.
I want to know what happened at Sunfall. What really happened.
For weeks each dawn in the tent city came with a new death.
Always in their sleep, no struggle.
The old, the infirm, sometimes the young.
Those who couldn't fight for the cause.
I should have realised then it was a calling.
Who would do such a thing?
They thought it was a curse, an evil spirit.
But it was only a man and a silent poison.
It took time to catch him, but we did.
We brought him before Bahavas for the Sun's judgement.
He's the one who put the bounty on you.
Yes. He thanked me for my diligence, then had his guards release the villain.
You see, it was he who ordered the culling.
Then they turned on us.
Should have died with my men, so their loyalty meant something.
Twenty years I gave to the Sun, for what?
Malice and murder?
As for honour, sacrifice, true sacrifice, the kind priests and rulers know nothing of?
It's all a fat joke.
If it's honour you seek the Sun Carja seem trustworthy.
A little stuck up, maybe, but trustworthy.
Those Carja once raided your Nora lands, raided every land we could reach.
It was the Sun's will.
I did what I was told, others did worse.
UTHID: But as their captain, I had–
ALOY: Uthid, I don't care what you did.
I can't absolve you.
But the Carja are changing their ways, you could too.
Perhaps. Avad doesn't understand what the Sun demands of its soldiers.
Perhaps he understands it too well.
Now you sound like the Blameless Marad.
I can believe you're a good man, but why go with the Shadow Carja in the first place?
Why serve them?
Because of Itamen, of course.
He was the one true Sun-King.
Itamen's just a child.
Yes, an untainted vessel.
I believed he was pure, but they used him, used our faith.
I can see that now, no shadows under a noonday sun.
Bahavas didn't need to disgrace my name, I did it myself serving a rotten throne.
I met someone who wants to get you out of this, a woman named Vanasha.
But first we need to get you out of here.
What are you?
You look like a hunter, you give orders like a soldier who's been—
UTHID: Mercenaries.
KIKUK: Should have stayed on the plains, Carja!
KIKUK: The mountains belong to us, Kikuk's Killers.
When we're done with you, you won't even leave an echo.
You didn't make it hard to be followed, almost as if you wanted to go out in a showdown.
Not much gets by you.
KILLER: On me!
UTHID: The fury of the Sun!
KILLER: Keep at it.
KIKUK: Move in! We'll send the rest as soon as they arrive.
KILLER: Grind them down.
KIKUK: It's up to you now, men. Rally, we can still finish them!
KILLER: You're not gonna see it coming.
KIKUK: Move in! We'll send the rest as soon as they arrive.
KILLER: Eat this!
KIKUK: Stand before us, fall beneath us.
UTHID: That won't be the last of them, follow me. I've stashed supplies up above.
UTHID: Up and over.
ODUND: A robust defence is the most satisfying to break.
ODUND: All right, Marvels. We brought the priest out here, so let's put on a show for him.
UTHID: I know that hood. We have unfinished business, Bahavas and I.
UTHID: This will be difficult. I think you rallied to a lost cause.
ALOY: I don't intend to die today, Uthid.
UTHID: I did. But you're starting to change my mind.
MARVEL: No matter, you'll feel my next arrow
UTHID: Look out, to your left!
ODUND: Not bad, but my Marvels thrive on adversity. Step it up, boys!
MARVEL: We're getting picked off!
MARVEL: …regroup!
MARVEL: Got all I need to finish you off!
MARVEL: We'll down them swiftly.
ALOY: That's the last of the Marvels.
UTHID: Bahavas thought he had enough fodder to keep him safe.
UTHID: Now there's hope for justice. Will you come with me?
UTHID: This won't be easy, Bahavas still has his personal guard.
ALOY: Snow chill, itches.
UTHID: Across there and we'll have him.
BAHAVAS: I had to come here myself to end your suffering, Uthid. And mine.
BAHAVAS: The outlanders led us here, and now that they are dead their price is most affordable.
BAHAVAS: But enough with needles. It's time for blades.
BAHAVAS: Remove them from the Sun's sight!
SHADOW CARJA: Sun's judgement upon you!
BAHAVAS: Make it hurt as the shadow falls upon them!
SHADOW CARJA: Focus on that one!
BAHAVAS: The Sun sets on your pathetic life, Uthid!
BAHAVAS: Kill the traitor! Kill the Nora!
BAHAVAS: Make it hurt as the shadow falls upon them!
ALOY: Okay, That helps.
BAHAVAS: The Sun sets on your pathetic life, Uthid!
UTHID: Press the attack!
BAHAVAS: Kill the traitor! Kill the Nora!
UTHID: Up to his perch!
BAHAVAS: Whatever deal you worked out with him, I'll double it! More than double it!
UTHID: No. I'm tired of this, Bahavas. The lies and the violence and your cheap scented oils.
UTHID: I don't suppose you'd kill yourself?
BAHAVAS: I had to! I had to! Prune the weak, or all the Carja in Shadow are doomed!
UTHID: This solves nothing, but may the Sun find some worth among your drying bones.
VANASHA: That was quite a fireworks show!
ALOY: You took your time.
VANASHA: I was busy. What do you think happened to Yun's Shunned, the other mercenary band?
VANASHA: And I had to organise passage to Meridian for a wanted man.
VANASHA: Give us a moment, Uthid. Girl talk.
You've had quite a day.
I never imagined Bahavas would blunder into his own trap.
What's going to happen at Sunfall now that Bahavas is dead?
Oh, it will be glorious!
The priests will panic.
There'll be infighting, skullduggery, and backstabbing, as they wrangle for power.
Best of all, they'll be distracted.
Bahavas, your life brought misery but your death is a flower that blooms in abundance.
Death suits him better than those robes ever did.
Remember Itamen and Nasadi, the child-king and his mother, guarded like hostages at Sunfall?
With Bahavas gone, no-one will be watching them.
I want to get them out, and I could use your help.
Kidnapping the Sun-King of the Shadow Carja is no small task.
It's not kidnapping. They want to go to Meridian, to safety.
How do you know that?
I've been posing as the Nasadi's handmaiden.
She's scared. For herself, of course, but mostly for Itamen.
Why do you care what happens to them?
Itamen is the Shadow Carja's figurehead.
If he defects, it will remove their last trace of legitimacy.
Beyond that, he's just a boy who clings to his mommy.
What's going to happen to Utid now?
Don't worry, you gave him a second life and I'll put it to good use.
He'll be welcomed in Meridian as a military adviser.
Hopefully, he can help Avad finish the Shadow Carja with as little bloodshed as possible.
What do you need to get Nasadi and Itamen out of Sunfall?
Sunfall is the easy part, I'll handle that.
The big fuss will be crossing the border to the Sundom.
Find my friend Three-Toed Huavid near the Branded Shore.
I hired his crew to sweep the path, so all you have to do is wait for me.
If this Huadiv has already cleared the area why do you need me?
Contingencies, little huntress.
Something will go wrong and I need protection I can count on. You.
I'll try not to disappoint.
UTHID: Are we bound for Meridian?
VANASHA: Only if you want to go, my dear.
UTHID: What choice do I have?
VANASHA: None at all, I was just being polite.
UTHID: What makes you think Avad will welcome me after I served his enemies?
VANASHA: He's a forgiving man.
VANASHA: Just smile a lot. You can smile, can't you?
VANASHA: No, that's … that's a grimace.
VANASHA: Nervous about going to Meridian?
UTHID: I've been a soldier for 20 years. I do not get nervous.
VANASHA: Not even around a pretty lady?
UTHID: I will not dignify that with a response.
Easy, easy!
You're down, the others haven't noticed.
Never know when I might need these.
Uh-oh, someone's grumpy.
There we go, information to help me override more machines.
So, Hephaestus is the source of the Cauldron data intrusions?
It's been forcing Cauldrons to make aggressive machines.
Deadlier and deadlier, year by year.
Why? And what, or who, is Hephaestus?
Another mystery to add to the list.
Just stay out of their way for now.
That hurt it!
That's it, I'm already gone.
Hunt's over, fight's on.
They're scanning for me.
Too slow!
Stocking up.
Keep quiet now.
Passed the test.
You're Three-Toed Huavid? Vanasha sent me. What happened?